Hi everyone. Welcome.
>> Hi everyone.
>> We'll just wait a couple of minutes to
make sure everyone's joining.
Hi Lucas. Hi Clara.
>> Hi.
>> Thank you for being so uh so numerous.
Hey Archer. Hey Sophie. if you want to
tell us where you're from as well so we
can have a bit of idea of uh which
country we'll be try to specify for
Paris. Okay. France.
Okay. Lot of messages. Hey everyone.
Okay. Mainly France. Um if French if
English is not your native or um you can
also add the subtitles which are
automated as well. Um so that can be
helpful as well if if needed. I saw some
in UK and Spain also.
>> Hey everyone, welcome.
Hey F,
thank you for joining.
We'll wait perhaps a minute before we
start.
Italy, hi Morocco. Why from far?
Hi everyone.
Um, let us know if it's too warm where
you are.
Great. I think it's 401. We'll come in a
we'll start in a second.
Great. I think we can get started then.
>> Yeah.
>> Cool. Well, welcome everyone. Super
happy to to do this webinar. Thank you
for joining. Um, we know it's a busy and
warm week for everyone. Um so quickly
we'll introduce oursel and then we'll
try to present to you why Reddit is um
your sec secret weapon. Um so my name is
Jules Shazo. I'm lead content strategist
at Eskimos. Been working there for the
past four years on the French and
English noun side. Um I've been working
with international clients across the
world and developing 360 degrees content
strategy for clients um through GEO SEO
now Reddit, Wikipedia etc. And I'm
joined here today by uh Flora.
>> Yes. Hi everyone. So I am floor like
Reddit. I'm a Reddit content strategist
at schemos and I'm basically doing like
some um semantic strategy for my client
and also I have a specification on
Reddit. That's why I'm here today with
Laura. Um so the promise of today of
this session is by should last around 45
minutes an hour. Um and by the 45
minutes mark you'll know if Reddit
really matters for your business. Um
what to do about it and how to measure
it as well. Um, quick heads up, there's
a Q&A at the end. Um, but please make
sure to ask us some questions as well
during the live. We'll try to answer it
at at the end of each sections. Um, so
feel free to to to ask us questions. Um,
but before quickly we go through our
slides, we just wanted to present
Eskimos in 30 seconds. So we are
15year-old company with over 200
consultants. We've have over a thousand
active clients in 70 countries. And um
we're just not we're not just an SEO
agency anymore. We cover really the full
search ecosystem from GEO, SEO, Amazon,
Tik Tok. Um and we spent a lot of our
research and and money into over€2
million euros per per year in research
and development um to really stay ahead
of the curve um for anything related to
GEO, Reddit, etc. Which is why we're
we're here today. um and we've had the
chance with our clients to um to try
those Reddit strategies that we'll talk
to you about today. So what we'll
present is not everything theoretical.
It's also some uh some real data um that
we've applied for our clients and for
Eskimos as well. Um so quick road map so
you know what what we'll answer today.
Um so we'll answer those five questions
which is why is Reddit suddenly winning
in SEO NGO? We see it more and more in
the SERPS. We see it in AI results in
citations. Um, and so what is happening
there and why is Google favoritism um
kind of that Reddit um channel? Should
your brand be on Reddit? Um, so and
what's the cost of staying out? So will
it be interesting um to see if for your
business and your niche, it's
interesting to position yourselves
there. Um, and actually how do you build
presence on Reddit? Um, there's a lot of
people have tried a lot of businesses
that have been burnt um being removed
from Reddit. Um, so we'll tell you how
to do it in the best way and manner. Um,
and finally, we'll try to measure the
impact for your business with the main
KPIs that you should follow and kind of
the Reddit ads um, as well to see if
it's useful. Um, if you want to skip
ahead, you can book a 30-minute call
with our sales team as well. Um, but
let's get started. Um, so for this um,
to respond to all those questions, we'll
go through this plan. Um, and at the end
of each section, we'll try to answer
your questions um, if they don't aren't
answered afterwards.
So maybe to start we want to do a quick
poll um and just ask you if you use like
Reddit uh for your personal use for
business both maybe or not at all. It
will permit us to know better how you
are using this platform and maybe we are
going to wait for few seconds and then
highlight some of your answers.
>> So you should see normally a poll coming
up um which you can answer and we'll
follow the results.
Um I'm seeing some people asking if the
session uh is recorded and if the
presentation will be sent. So yes, of
course the presentation will be sent
with the recording. Um so don't worry if
someone of your team is not here. Um
we'll be able to share with them
afterwards.
Okay. I'm seeing a lot of people are
using for the personal use. People are
still new for it.
Okay.
Some people are not using Reddit at all.
So, it's a great place to know how to
use it.
>> Okay. So, most of you are still new to
it. I see other bits that use it for
both. I think um
yeah, a bit of D, a lot of D,
>> a lot of them. Yeah,
>> I think it's what what this question
matter today is because a lot of people
use it for personal use. Um but how we
use it for Reddit professionally is very
different. Um and so that's the exact
gap and opportunity that we'll talk
about um in a minute. Okay. So mainly a
lot of these so new to people to Reddit.
That's great. We'll present Reddit as
well um for you to be more familiar with
it. Ready? Okay.
>> Yes.
>> Let's go.
>> Um so we've seen that there's a lot of
people that are familiar with Reddit, of
course. Um and as recent numbers have
come out, there's over 450 million
weekly active Unix on Reddit. Um, and
that makes it currently the third most
visited website in the US. Um, just
behind Google and YouTube. So, of
course, it's it's kind of huge. It's
been created in August 2025, so it's
even older than Instagram, Twitter, Tik
Tok, etc. And so, it's it's its base and
how it's built hasn't changed that much
since. And it's really a Wii platform.
So, it's not a MI platform in a sense of
personal use. It's really the goal is
for the community. uh it's anonymous and
you don't really gain anything for being
known there. It's more for the goal of
higher purpose of being uh of being um
of providing information. Um and so what
we've seen is that in the IPO that
happened in March 2024 um the p the the
company become publicly listed and is
now worth over 25 billion. And uh and
that really changed kind of the company
in terms of monet monetization pressure.
Um, and so that's why perhaps it
happened mainly on the AI deals and what
we've seen with Google and OpenAI as
well. Um, and so the main question that
we're going to ask ourselves right now
is why does Reddit dominates um, SEO and
JO? Um and so to better understand its
impact on Jio currently when we look at
the sources and kind of what's how the
place of Reddit in AI we can see that's
the top um source that is being
mentioned by um by AI and and by LLN um
and and um Google um open AAI as well um
and so we can see that um it's the first
cited platform in AI search and so um
what's interesting is that it converts
as well dramatically higher. Um, so when
we say it's not a channel, a social
channel anymore, it's really the layer
of search underneath itself. Um, so not
only is Reddit everywhere an AI answer
as well, but the traffic AI sends you
converts dramatically harder as well.
Um, but to present to you a bit, you
know, Reddit before we get a bit more
into it. So how does Reddit work? Um, so
basically you've got those subreddits
which are communities. Um and anyone can
create a subreddit. Um there's mainly a
lot of different subreddits over 100,000
and each one have its own rules,
moderators and focus. Um the biggest
ones if you want to know of subreddits
are over 100,000 uh 60 million sorry uh
participants inside of them. So it's
kind of huge subreddits um with our
activities. On those subreddits you got
moderators that are volunteers, not
Reddit employees that really define the
community um aspect of it. and uh can
break um implement the rules, you can
get banned, etc. So, they're really the
ones that are responsible for those
threads. Um and inside those subreddits,
you've got threads, which are posts and
comments. Um and how it works is you've
got up votes and down votes. Up votes,
of course, push the content up and down
votes bury it. Um so, it's really the
crowd that ranks the um every piece of
content, not the al algorithm.
how it overall works as well is that
you've got a karma which is your
reputation score. Um, and so that's
super important because it's it presents
how much of a help you are to the
community. Um, so it's really earned.
You can't really buy it. Um, and that's
how it's um how it works on on Reddit.
What's interesting is that um you gain
karma by adding posts and gaining up
votes or comments and gaining up votes.
However, they're not all equal. For
example, if you post on a news section
or or for example um on quantum physics
and you get a lot of vote votes, it'll
have more impact than if you for example
get a lot of votes on um a funny uh
subreddit for example. Um and of course
the front page is dynamic. So what you
see really depends on the the subs that
you join, what you upvote, what you
comment. And so what that will be the
aspect that vary um for you instead of
the others. And so why does this really
matter for your brand? It's it really
shows that it's a trust machine. Um and
that uh Google and LLM is exactly
looking for that. Um it's more of these
EAT criteria that we've seen more
recently arrived. Um and that is how
Google um is is why Google is interested
in Reddit. It's basically eat
materialized. Um and so what is EAT? It
shows experience, expertise, authority,
and trust to Google. And so, Reddit fits
because it shows experience from users.
It's really firsthand users giving their
feedback of an experience of a product
of a solution. Um, it's expertise.
You've got subreddits on any topics uh
that can go quite in detail. Um, you've
got authority. Um, so with those karma,
there's account history. So, that's
trust that is verifiable. Um, and the
trust is also coming from the up votes
and the down votes and from those
moderators as well that will ban the
content that's not helpful. Um, and so
overall Reddit is basically structurally
immune to the AI content flood um that
Google is fighting. And so that's why in
February 2024 we've seen this big deal
that's happened with Google with over 60
million um US dollars per year. And so
that allows Googles to license Reddit's
content to train Gemini and put um real
content data into the search. Um just
after that we've seen the core update um
that the goal was to remove anything
that's too AI written and really bring
more help helpful basically content to
the SER. Um and then step by step we've
seen the introduction of AI overview in
2024 and the quality of RA guidelines
updated. Um, so those are all linked to
um AI content um that's not helpful to
the to the public and so that is why
Reddit has started to appear more in the
SERs and appear more in AI results as
well. And when we look at the results on
the SER um so we've added here a graph
from CRIX you can see that the
visibility is growing quite rapidly um
um from then. So what is the the the
graph is not really normal. Um as we
work in SEO we've seen that many time.
It seems that it's almost something like
algorithmic favoritism. Um and so we see
that Reddit has taken off place in the
SERs. I've put a few examples beneath.
You can see with nail cutter you can see
that Reddit is in the top results and uh
and for example when you're comparing
two softwares as well Reddit will
usually be at the top of the sub. Um and
so now Reddit really appears in 82% of
Google searches and is the first um
platform that is cited by AI and 15% of
AI overview answers site Reddit. Um so
it's playing this um it's having this
huge impact on AI and LLM and so now
it's it's not only being cited um but
it's also being um the data um is is
trained on Reddit as well. So, OpenAI,
for example, signed a deal with them in
2024. um and it's used all of Reddit's
data um to train its LLMs on um so what
it what happened which I think is quite
interesting in um in 2025 as well in
September is I don't know if you
remember if you follow the citations
from your gen keywords um but basically
there was a huge drop with Reddit not
being cited anymore and um from 15% to
0% almost and what we've seen is that
actually what was happening is not that
Reddit uh sorry, OpenAI JGPD doesn't
site um Reddit anymore. It's more that
it's um not quoting it um when talking
about its sources. But an NHF analysis
found that actually um
Reddit is still being quoted. It's not
being cited. Um, and why is that is
because Reddit um, and OpenAI have this
deal and um, and OpenAI now is using
this uh, Reddit Foundation for training
its LLMs. It's still using a bit of a re
realtime retrieval. Um, so Reddit is
also in the answers um, which you'll
mainly see on on Google's LLM and
Perplexity. Um, but really what to
remember is that Reddit has this
invisibible influence um, uh, across the
LLMs. Um, and their co-founder and CEO
Steve Hoffman even said that LLMs would
not exist as we know them without
Reddit. Um, and that I think is quite
true. It's a it's kind of a strong
statement um, but accurate when you look
at kind of the training corpora. Reddit
is both the training data and the real
time citation source. Um, so I think
that's a unique platform that um, no
other platform has basically. Um, and I
we think that's why there's five main
reasons why you should be on Reddit
today. Um, the first one is really to
push your search visibility really
appear on those searches and and search
intentions that buyers are looking for.
So perhaps best, you know, nail cutter
for me or perhaps their hair haird
dryer. Um, so really applying for search
visibility. The second one is really to
push your AI presence. So as Reddit is
shaping how LLM and AIU describe um
yourself in your category, you can
either be there or you by default or you
can be really active in it and kind of
shape how those response are going to
change. The third one is to really
control this brand truth and you can
control your own story uh by making sure
that what is being said on Reddit and
those platforms is is correct. Um and
finally the last two is pushing your eat
signal. So really building that trust
that you can't fake anymore and you
can't buy. Um and finally one that I
think a lot of um people are missing
currently is that using that audience
intelligence. Um so really using those
um comments from um those redditors will
be super helpful. Um, so what we've
seen, for example, Hrefs, the platform
for SEO, has every two years since 2015,
did ask me anything on Reddit to see um
what people thought of their products
and if they could do anything to improve
it. Um, and I think that's super
interesting because uh what we've seen
and we you could see at the top comments
from Reddit and anything that was of
help for Hrefs have been implemented in
their platform. And I think that's why
the SEO has understood um at that time
that posting it on using their advice
will be super useful not only now to
build the product but also now being
cited in in AI and and in SER. One thing
to remember though is that all actors
are not impacted the same. Um, so I'm
not going to tell you if you're a SAS or
an e-commerce that it will have the same
impact. Um, but it will be critical for
most of you. So that includes SAS, B2B,
fintech, e-commerce, anything related to
traveling. Um, that will be very
important for you um to to be present
there because people are usually looking
for best um, you know, searches with
comparisons. Um, and really the trust is
is really decisive there. perhaps where
there's a bit less impact and the
exposure is perhaps less important. it's
really in the institutional and public
sector um where really when you look at
it official sources really prefer um are
preferred by AI engines rather than
Reddit for example
and um and what you can do for that uh
if you want to do a little test to see
if it's important in the niche you are
in is really to type your top commercial
query um if Reddit appears in the top 10
for example in the SER results um if it
appears in discussions and forum or if
it's appearing as well in the AI
interviews
um um overview, sorry, AI overview, that
means that you're greatly concerned. Um
so if you're seeing any results, you
know, shaping um from Reddit, don't
hesitate to use it um as this will have
a massive impact.
And so I think one last question comes
from, you know, this evolution of Reddit
is really what you lose from not being
present on Reddit. And so I think
there's a few elements that you lose
which is one opportunities now you know
60% of AR searches end without a click
and so um that means that AI overview is
present that means that people are
searching on LM and so that mean that
they're looking at you know what those
LLMs are promoting rather than your
websites. Um so that's a big loss of
opportunities there and conversions you
lose visibility as well. Um so as you
we've been say when you a lot of people
type you know brand plus Reddit over 30
bit two billion searches per year. Um so
if you're not there then you're kind of
missing on that visibility aspect as
well or at least you're not controlling
it. Um the third one is really trust. Um
now people really trust what people are
saying on those platforms more and more.
Um so it's essential to be there. Um you
miss uh you missed the decision. Um so
if people use Reddit to make decisions
and finally you're missing validation
and authority um as we've seen a bit
earlier EAT criteras are essential and
those really come from um from those
platforms and now I'll let um Flora
respond to a few questions and uh
present to you as well how to be present
on Reddit then.
>> Yes. So now that you understand why uh
ready dominates and how it works with
jewels uh we are going to dive uh into
the strategy that work uh to build a
lasting presence uh in the platform.
Um so the first point will be that most
brands uh treat Reddit like another
social platform. Uh the key with Reddit
is that you earn trust. You earn trust
by contributing, answering question, uh
giving some helpful content, sharing
real experience. Um and you will help
the community and this long before you
even mention your brand. Uh so you have
to keep in mind uh that Reddit isn't an
audience, it's really a community. And
every subreddit had its own rules, its
own codes, its own moderators like Drew
said. um and the redditors the users of
Reddits actively reward authenticity. Uh
so that's why I put here um three main
traps brands uh that um sorry three main
traps that brand fall into. The first
one will be to push content like you do
on Twitter or LinkedIn because you are
broadcasting like corporate uh messages
uh without even taking into account the
question of the user uh in the first
place. The second one will be to expect
visibility without contribution. As I
said, when you are on Reddit, you have
to contribute to have uh visibility. So,
no participation equals no visibility.
Um and then uh get banned and wonder
why. uh every subreddit has its own
rules and um all the moderators are
watching that you are following the
rules and so if you if you are breaking
the rules you can be removed or even
banned and we are going to show you some
really great example of brands that do
not follow uh the main rules of uh
Reddit.
So actually the the rule is pretty
simple. You have to contribute first,
earn trust second and speak third and so
that you understand the mindset of the
platform uh we are going to uh see what
it means in practice.
So I saw some um questions uh on the
side um speaking about um using account
how they can do it. So here here is like
a 15-day uh warm-up sequence. Um and so
the first thing will be um before even
thinking uh to post on Reddit, you need
to know that Reddit uh anti-pam filters
are pretty brutal. So if you are new to
to Reddit and you go on the platform and
first 24 hours you are posting uh like a
promote uh message, you can get
automatically banned. um be even if no
one saw it, even if you didn't get
downvoted, it's because your um your
account is too new. So, um for that you
have to follow some uh basic rules. And
if you're thinking by uh to buy
pre-warmed account, it is not really
relevant because it's better, it's more
interesting and more natural to create
your own and um like build it.
So the first part will be to create an
account with a verified email, enable uh
enable to FA verification. You can add a
profile photo, a bio like fill your
account like a normal person. Um then
the first phase will be to observe only.
So you go on the homepage, you do
nothing else. So you just scroll and see
uh what are the um the post about. Uh
the third um phase will be to join and
read. Join in read that means you can
join two or three subreddits related to
your sector to your niche. You go on
that uh subreddits. You read the
threads. Um you can read the comments
and check what are people are saying,
how they are talking uh about uh some
specific topic. And here you do not vote
and you do not comment yet. it will be
uh done on the free on the fourth sorry
um part that will be comment with value.
So here when you um go on those
celebrity that you follow you can start
to to publish maybe one to two um answer
a day uh you answer the question you
share some insight some expert insight
uh but you do not uh push your brand
yet. And then the fifth um um step will
be uh the post you can like post and it
is where the real work start. And so
when your account is warmed up you maybe
ask yourself what kind of account I'm
going to create how I'm going to talk to
the community and that's we are what we
are going to see. So this one is uh this
slide is related to uh if you want to
push a brand or personal expert account.
I saw also this question on the uh
question tab. So uh basically
you have two way to show yourself on
Reddit in a legitimate way. Um some
brands can do both but you maybe need to
start with one and it will depend on
your goal, your sector, your
competitors, what they are doing and how
com comfortable you are with uh maybe uh
speaking on your with your own brand.
The first one is brand account. So it's
your company name. You have fully you
are fully visible. Uh the affiliation is
really clear and ready uh ready
tolerates it. Uh if you are transparent,
authenticity will be the key with on on
Reddit and the trust selling here is
pretty low because it's like corporate
by nature and Redditors can smell like a
tone like marketing tone a mile away. So
you have to make sure that you uh are uh
speaking to your um audience the right
way. Um and how you can shine with this
kind of account is through AMAs as Jules
say like ask me anything. um session,
official responses, crisis management.
Uh it's those kind of moments uh when
the people want to hear from your brand
or if you already have a credibility in
your community uh or if your community
is like pretty active or demanding, it
really it's really uh interesting. Um
and the risk that you can have with th
this kind of account um if if your tone
is too corporate too much corporate for
the platform uh you can be downvoted or
not banned but highlighted um by uh PR
team or press etc. And I'm going to show
you after some use cases.
Then the second one is personal expert
account. It can be a user, it can be a
founder, an employee and consu
consultant like someone real. Uh here
the trusting is pretty high because
human trust humans. It's interesting for
organic contribution to push your brand
name um and Reddit tolerates it as long
as it's authentic. And the risk that you
can have with this kind of um account is
if your history looks fake. uh if you
have an empty profile, if you post like
weirdly, you have a weird posting
patterns. Uh with those kind of uh
thing, you can get shadowban.
>> Yeah. One thing to to add as well on
that, I've seen a lot of questions on if
you should say that you work in the
company. Um you you we recommend you
saying that you're for example um an
employee in the company and that you're
helping the community. Um the risk is if
you don't say it um then there's a
higher risk of you being banned. Um and
one thing that can be really dangerous
for your brand is that for example in an
important subreddit um you can get
basically banned your your accounts but
also you can get your main keyword so
your brand name for example can be
removed. So every mention of your brand
name will be not tolerated. Um and so
then you'll disappear entirely from that
subreddit which will be quite impactful
on AI results. Um so we recommend you to
be quite transparent and say that you're
working in free marketing that you're
helping to you know build an agency for
example or you're helping to make LLMs
faster I don't know but um really don't
hesitate to be transparent of although
because the consequences can be quite
important if you're banned or or even
your brand keyword is is removed.
>> Yes.
Uh so then uh there is some real example
sorry some real example uh of what I was
saying between um um brand account or a
personal expert account. For example on
the left you have ClickUp Dualingo or
Cursor AI that have uh created their own
community with their uh own rules. Uh so
it helps uh users to uh maybe have some
answers of the brand directly or other
user of ClickUp or Dualingo to to answer
uh their questions directly and you can
highlight some post um that are really
important for uh the community.
Um then on the right side you have some
personal experts as uh Jules said uh
it's like a really good example. um the
GD2M
official is the founder I think of this
company and he is speaking on um like
directly to the community and he's
saying hey I'm the founder of this
company and I can help you with that and
he's giving really good insight and
really good expert um questions um and
also he's um linking his website too so
that can be interesting the other one uh
Simon
Hailberg, I think, is um he's not like
um he's not speaking behalf a company.
He's just an expert that knows his
subject and just answering questions uh
on different uh subreddits.
Uh now we can see if you need or if you
want transparency or anonymity. Um and
first of all, here's something uh
crucial about Reddit. It has an
unwrightened but strictly enforced rule
around transparency. So you don't have
to reveal everything but you cannot like
actively deceive and the community has
built a nearperfect uh detector for
inauthenticity.
Sorry. Um so here's the four things that
uh Reddit tolerates. The first one will
be disclose and win. So if you say uh
I'm the founder of this company uh I'm
biased but blah blah blah I can help you
with this problem I have the solution my
uh solution helps um this amount of
people and also you are answering the
questions um it is generally helpful so
it's interesting and you want to help
first then push your brand
the second one will be testimonial uh
work sharing really uh real client
stories real client client experience.
Um so you are contributing and not
promoting uh first then the uh you can u
use um ready doesn't need your real
name. It needs just your real track
record and to know that you are a real
person uh behind uh this account. Um and
also one mention one mention of your
product naturally uh is okay at the end
of a great answer. You will see on
Reddit if you go on on the platform you
will see sometimes on the comments
people um like write long comments uh
with a lot of context and lot of
information. Uh so pushing your brand or
your service or solution is not the
first point like the point of the
answer. uh but also you are giving uh
some uh genuine uh information in
context and answers.
Now, um, oh, sorry. Maybe I go on the
other side if it's not really clear. As
I said, not respecting the rules. It's
like the main point on Reddit. Uh, copy
pasting answers. As I said, if you go on
multiple Reddits, subreddits and do the
same answer always and always or copy
pasting your LinkedIn and Twitter uh
post, it is not okay. Asking for up
votes. Um if you ask external um people
to go massively uh up vote um an answer
it can be flagged also. And the last um
point will be uh if you have no uh
history on your account and then
suddenly you are pushing uh your uh
product. So it's not okay. Um so here
it's like pretty clear uh you have to be
transparent with what you want to to
offer to the platform. you have to
contribute first and never to try to to
gain the system or change uh the rules
of uh every subreddit.
Um so now that everything um this those
information are clear um I'm going to
show you how you can choose your subies.
So
the tagline will be sniper not shotgun.
That means that you have to it's better
to be precise and to know where you want
to go before just like spraying content
across 20 different subreddits and
getting nowhere with that. Um so here is
the framework that I use uh through
basically three types of community. Uh
the first one I um it's the niche I um I
think the word is niche. uh it's like
the uh separate SEO SAS marketing the
huge one uh your core audience will be
there uh but you have high competitions
uh strict rules also because there is a
lot of people um and uh so if you go on
those kind of subreddits and you are
doing the work in the in a good way uh
you can uh be reward massively. The
second one will be adjacent. Ajson as
you can see it is more um um it's small
business freelance or very specific one
mana man manager it because you have the
subre manager the huge one but you have
more specific like dev manager uh etc.
Uh it is people who uh need your product
but are not searching for it yet. Um and
there is um lower defenses and maybe
people can uh discover your brand more
easily. Um and also um if you if you go
on those kind of uh subreddits you can
if you have um service or product uh a
lot of product or different vertical uh
it can be interesting to target a
specific audience on those kind of
subreddits. And the third one uh you do
not have to forget and put uh aside the
local part. you have a lot of sub rates
related to cities related to specific um
um area in the world for example uh I
have in mind e-commerce Brazil for
example so it's targeting the Brazil and
the e-commerce sector uh so it's really
uh great for local brands uh for example
if you search if someone is searching
best account accountants in the 11th
district uh that's can be a warm lead
and there is less uh competition then um
uh when we compare to the niche or
adjacent one. So it really interesting
uh for you. Um before you post I put it
I put uh uh four step uh to do a quick
uh like audit if it's a good subre for
you. You have to read the rules. Um
check what are the top 10 uh all times
post that are working on the specific
subreddit.
um check if the moderators are like
banning a lot of post and what are the
path of the user on this specific
subreddit and also read the tone. You
have to match the tone of voice. I will
uh show you later but you have to um um
really match the tone of voice of Reddit
and do not use like a corporate tone of
voice. And on the side you have uh two
tips uh in order to uh see if a
celebrity is relevant for uh your
company. You can do like a site
reddit.com plus your keyword or your
brand and see where a user are talking
about you or your specific uh keyword
that you want to target.
>> That is to type on Google on the
>> Yeah. to type on Google. Sorry. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. And also you can uh use
Reddit ads freely when you set up an
account. uh you can uh have like free
subreit suggestions that can be
interesting and then um always you do
like the four step subreddits audit
analysis in order to check uh if it's
relevant for you
uh so here are some example related to
specific uh sector for example the HR
solution services when we go on the
niche we have the huge one human
resources managers ask managers when we
go on the adjacent it's more specific we
can talk about um to IT managers or
remote work if our HR solution is
dedicated to this um or employee
management if we have a solution that uh
help uh employee management and on the
local you can see that we have
um basically the huge one United
Kingdom, Paris, Boston, French etc. and
we also have human resources UK. So you
can find uh your sector plus the local
area that you want to target.
finance, bank and insurance company.
Also on the niche personal finance,
investing adjacent you can uh target
maybe entrepreneur or the tax topic for
the professional and on the local you
have um legal advice UK and other uh
kind of uh local subreddits.
And then third uh use case uh if you are
a e-commerce or retail company you have
the huge one e-commerce small business
uh or ask retail that focus um retail
espec especially the adjacent one will
be e-commerce marketing uh drop shipping
for example or supply chain logistic if
it's really specific uh to your uh
sector and as I said the local I I use
this example but e-commerce BR that
e-commerce Brazil
small business in UK if it's really what
you want to target.
So here are some real example. Uh so now
that you chose your subreddit, you chose
the kind of account that you want to
create. Uh you finally have to post uh
with a brand intent. Uh but how you can
write it? So I put here two format that
works on Reddit. The first one will be
the brand experience. Um, so it's like a
basic brand format. You show up at the
founder or an employee or consultant or
someone that work for this specific
solution. Um, and you are uh answering
question. You can say that obviously
you're biased because you work here, but
you can give a real information, a real
answer and generally help uh the
community. And uh also what is important
you uh have to not just push your brand
or solution you add you need to add more
expert information and answering the
questions that the user is um is putting
on the subreddit.
Uh the second format will be experienced
user. Uh here uh you are posting maybe
as a customer and um um or user but not
like the brand itself. Um I've uh
highlighted some part uh that you can
see uh related to the tone of voice. Uh
for example, not going to lie, uh you're
not speaking the same way that you are
speaking on on LinkedIn or Twitter. If
you are the founder of the company, you
are you will have like a more casual way
of speaking. Uh like you can like uh
send a message to a friend that you want
uh uh really that you really want to
help. Um you can also the second part
that I've highlighted was automages felt
robotic at first that means that you can
admit some uh flows uh not huge one that
can u be um negative for your business
but little one that you're aware of
maybe some people uh pushed it on uh
your um on on on the side like the user
of the services uh that you're pushing.
Um and you can also there is two way
here is a way that you do not mention
competitors. You say no idea if there
are better alternatives out there. I've
put I took this um solution. It was
really great. But there is some other uh
brands that I saw that are uh sometimes
pushing competitors. It is when you are
comfortable with that by uh saying there
is a list of other competitors. you can
like choose the one that you want to
push or you can just talking about
alternatives that exist.
So it's two format that uh that uh exist
and um just below uh it works because
you are answering the question you uh
can say that you're there is bias if uh
if there is uh you need to have a
conversional tone not like a corporate
one um you can name friction point or
flows of your solutions uh very in a
transparent way um and you can mention
uh alternatives if you
So that's why uh those two formats
worked.
Um here's some example. On the left side
you have a founder of companies that
talk um uh for themselves. So they are
saying that are they are the founder or
they are working on this company. Uh
they can add link to this specific
website. And on the right you have
experienced user and here you have
different format. you have uh people
that are think that they are using the
solution and are really happy and they
are pushing uh the brand solution. Uh
and I know that there is brand uh behind
those account uh and the second example
that you have in the middle is the one
that I told you that is pushing other uh
competitors within the answer.
So now you know uh what to do if the
half uh is the only half uh the job then
now you uh want to know what are the
mistakes that you can uh do and what um
you do not have to do because you can be
banned or as uh Jules said you can uh
your brand can be erased of the
subreddit uh uh permanently. The first
one will be posting promo in week one as
I said multiple accounts with the same
IP address ready can flag like IP
fingerprinting. Uh so if you have
several accounts in like on the specific
um computer that you have and you are
managing all the account within the same
IP uh you can be flagged. Um if you
write in a two marketing language like a
ton of voice also um commenting on dead
threads that means if uh there is uh
threads that is not uh live u until 2022
it is not relevant for you to go and
push your brand because there is no uh
life behind uh this post. Um if you are
in ignoring sorry tools it can be very
um it can have like a huge damage on
your brand and also chasing uh karma you
can have a lot of karma on specific uh
subreddit but it is not relevant to your
sector or your audience. It is more uh
interesting to have less you know
specific like adjacent subreddit as I
said um that will be uh more interesting
for you.
Uh so now we are going to uh go on the
use cases. Um so first a success story
that we lived ourselves with Eskimos and
then we are going to show you two cases
uh to show you what can happen if you
use it wrong uh like it was the case for
EA Sport and Nissen.
Um so for Eskimos what we've done we
didn't like do a test. It was like a
real strategy. Uh we wanted to create a
community. We build our own community.
Uh so here uh you can go on Reddit and
follow us. Uh if you uh want more um
insight, more information on SEO, go AI
and everything uh regarding those topic.
And we gained a lot of u members as you
uh see on the on the left the top that
shows the amount of members that we
gained uh near 900 members. um um until
I think it was October, since October.
And then um basically we have an average
of uh 33 uh 36 sorry K uh impressions um
a month uh on the different um um posts
that we publish on the um Eskimos
community.
The second step was we worked on
external subits uh by respecting every
community rules. That's why we are not
banned and we we can push our Eskimos uh
in a more transparent way. Uh those uh
on the left you can see some SER that we
worked on. It was uh related to SAS
marketing uh LLM or AI directly. So we
as you saw we uh focus on our audience
our niche and where we want to uh find
those people.
>> Perhaps we're getting a bit short on
time if we want to answer questions. Um
here we have a few success cases and
negative cases afterwards. Um we'll
share the presentation with you
afterwards. Um so you'll have all the
information on what was the the good
practices and the negative practices. Um
I think there's a good case right after
about a disaster case with EA which is
the most downvoted um
>> posts. Um but we'll we'll make sure to
to answer your questions as I see you
have loads already. Um I saw a few ones
that I perhaps want to answer already
before um going to the next one is the
first one is um does the French market
as I see there's a lot of French people
impacted as well. Um yes it's quite
impacted as well of course to a lower
degree than in the US. Um but it's
progressing quite rapidly as well. Um so
AI overview don't exist in France. So of
course Google's not going to um show up
in the SER. Um but it's will arrive at
some point. Um same with LLMs. So it's
uh it's still important to a higher
degree. Um, and I think I saw another
question that was in in interesting as
well, which was, um, is it worth posting
on Reddit if, um, none of my, you know,
potential customers read Reddit? And,
uh, and that's why we think it's quite
important because your, um, potential
customers probably very necessarily use
AI. And since they're using Reddit, you
know, as a platform for their um,
information and and to train their data,
they're going to use it anyways. Um, so
technically even if they don't go on
Reddit, they're going to use AI, LLM,
Open AI, JPD, which will site Reddit.
Um, so it's very important to make sure
that um, even if you're not um, your
customers are not on Reddit, um, you
should try to be. And finally, before I
go to the last question was interesting,
which was um, what's the goal if I just
talk and help people instead of citing
my brand? It's not about not citing your
brand. It's building up your karma um to
in to sight your baron afterwards in a
natural way. Um otherwise you're going
to get banned. So that's why we
recommend it's just about building up. I
I saw a few people as well talking about
in the comments um that you need a
minimum of karma to publish on some
subreddits and that's true as well to
comment. Um so that's why building up
your profile which is brand or personal
and both can be useful um is important.
Um so we'll look at the last questions
towards the end. Um but we just want to
go through the um how to measure your
Reddit ROI and attribution. Um and so we
think that there are five KPIs that
actually matter a lot. It's the share of
voice in LM. So I was just talking about
that um how often is your site is your
brand cited versus competitors um on you
know through citation or for how the um
the LLM has data has been trained. Um
the second KPI is really Reddit mentions
um and sentiment. Um so what's the
volume behind it? What's a sentiment
trend? Is it positive? What people say
behind your brand? Is it negative? Um,
and for that there's a lot of different
tools. We've actually built a tool in
house which we'll quickly show you right
afterwards which is called Reddit Plus.
Um, but you can use other tools which
are free or or available. Um, and the
third one is the branded search. So
really look at your brand plus Reddit
what comes up. Um, and if you have a
very small brand perhaps nothing will
come up but you can build it up. um as
you probably have the hope that your
brand will grow and and people will
search for it afterwards.
>> Yeah. The um fourth one will be uh the
third one will be Ben search uh lift
when you go on growth you can check the
growth of your brand plus Reddit and
then the AI overview presence uh because
you know as Jules said uh AI overview
chat and LMS use uh Reddit so you can
search your high intent queries that are
uh citing uh Reddit within the AI
overview and then uh it will be the
self-report uh attribution and you can
check uh uh how um people uh search for
you and um for example in free form or
contact form they can uh say that uh
their users are ready to uh find you.
Quick uh thing uh about uh referral
traffic on JA4. Uh you can uh send real
click to your site through Reddit. Uh
especially if you're a founder of a
company, if you have your community, you
can put link uh that goes to your
website. Uh we added some bullet points
um that speaks about that and also uh
the second layer it will be uh
conversion. Uh you can track them
through uh those uh for um different
bullet point. And also um it will be
interesting to uh see the last one that
is assisted conversion um on JA4 because
you will think that uh Reddit is not
relevant or doesn't work. But if you uh
just check the last click maybe uh but
sometimes Reddit users on Reddit find
your brand then go on Google and then
find um your brand and then convert and
it will be interesting to uh check this
assisted uh path. Uh and for that we uh
mentioned some uh tips in order to put
uh this in place.
>> Exactly. But one thing to keep in mind
is that really it's not Reddit that
directly generate leads. It really
generates the conditions on which um
lead happened. Um so you don't really
measure Reddit by clicks. You don't
expect last click and you don't judge it
after one month only. The right question
I think to ask for your boardroom and
for yourself is how many leads did re um
isn't how many leads did Reddit generate
this month is without Reddit how much
more would my customer acquisition cost
because if your competitors are on
Reddit and you're not in six months now
you know perhaps their cost of
acquisition will be 30% 40% lower as
you're not being present on AI. So, I
think that's more the mindset that you
need to appro um approach when posting
on Reddit. Um and and to look at those
KPIs, we'll quickly present our tool
that we've built in house um to still
have five minutes afterwards to respond
to your questions
>> quickly.
>> I'll try to answer a few questions in
between
>> here. Okay. So, normally you can see uh
my screen here. Do you want to answer
some questions maybe? Okay, perfect.
>> So, we know that Reddit is for now not
as well understood as goes and atos we
want to focus our work uh by helping our
clients uh to have the best of the
visibility that they can have uh with
those uh key innovations. Uh so that's
why we built uh Reddit Plus. It's a tool
that we can you can find on our um
Eskimos app esimos application and it's
launching soon. Uh so first of all uh
you have this interface here.
Um the first part will be the overview
part. Uh it is where you can see uh the
main um metrics that you want uh to
track. So here you have the main
visibility but visibility is like a
basic feature that we have uh on our
tools. Um but we wanted to give you more
actionable insight to make uh sure you
will be able to prioritize and have
relevant impact. So here you can see
just below you have uh two um
opportunities uh tab. So, for example,
if your brand is attacked or mentioned
badly, uh we already added filters in
order for you to um have the the the
main spot the more important spot
publication where you want uh to have
the a massive impact.
Uh then on the left you can add uh you
you see that there is a monitoring and
brainsport. The monitoring one is
related to your um your non-breeding
keyword. So on the tool you can add
non-breeding keyword. If someone is uh
talking about CRM CR CRM sorry software
or best C CRM software um those kind of
um uh keyword will be tracked and you
will be able to see them in inbox in
inbox we are uh focusing our work on
indexed posts. So some posts can be
indexed on uh Google SER. So here you
will be able to sew them um if the
sentiment of the uh the question is
negative, positive, neutral and you will
also see the live post on Reddit.
And for example, when you choose um this
one, what are the best AI powered CRM
tools? You can click on it and you can
have um here you can have um like AI
answers uh where you can choose if you
want uh to be helpful, personal,
curious, direct um and it will be like
generated automatically. Here you can
modify it, adapt it to your tone of
voice, pushing your brand if you want in
more natural way and transparent way and
then you can copy paste it and it will
open Reddit and you can like put it on
Reddit directly.
Um then you have the brand side here.
The brands is um focused it's like the
same mechanism as the monitoring one but
is focused on brands your brands and
your competitors brands. So here you can
add uh the the competitors and their
alias in their um like keyword plus
brand names. You can have the analysis
of that how um their um volume of uh
activity um on different subreddits. the
main celebrity that they are mentioned
on uh yours also obviously the user that
are uh posting and the percentage
percentage of mentions sorry and what is
um different uh with the monitoring tab
is that you have the comments tab here
the comments it is when a competitors uh
is mentioned and you're not you can be
able to click open the tab and do the
same and check if you want to answer or
that by uh creating um like an direct
answer through AI and then modify it and
and do the modification that you want.
So here are the key um aspect of the
tool uh that are really helpful when you
want to start um um visibility and and
strategy on Reddit because go is like
the majority of person understand and
use it and match their SEO strategy in
order to be visible in on JO but um
there is less person that understand
Reddit. So um with the time passing like
company will go find agency to have uh
to put in place a ready strategy and so
they will be more um um like um and you
will have the one that do the strategy
and the other that doesn't though the
gap will be um important. That's why we
are creating those tools to help uh our
clients the best way we can.
Maybe if you have questions regarding
the tool, we can answer that after and
go uh dive in a little bit.
>> Yeah.
>> Here.
Yeah.
So, um we can go quickly on Reddit ads.
Uh so on Reddit ads you have different
uh type of format that can help you on
your organic strategy on Reddit. Um the
first one uh will be the text. It can be
like a title short body with a link uh
within the page that you want to push.
It's a native format uh and it blades it
in blends sorry good within the feed. Uh
it is good for discussions, community
engagement, awareness. Uh the second one
is in age uh is a static uh visual
headline and CTA. It simple and in fast
to produce and it is easy to AB uh test.
You can uh use this one to promote uh do
a product launch uh things like that.
Then you have videos. Uh it's autoplay
video in feed. Uh you can go um through
15 minutes uh of video. Um, and you need
to add the subtitles, but because uh 85%
of the video are watched without sound,
so it will be silly to not add those.
And it can be interesting to um if you
want to push brands, product demo,
storytelling. And the last one will be
carousel add two to six swipeable cards
uh with independent uh title and CTAs uh
if you want to showcase products, case
study, etc.
>> Exactly. Um, and just perhaps to to
conclude quickly as as we're a bit short
on time and we know you have maybe
meetings right after. Um, is that we
think you should definitely be present
on Reddit. Um, it's just part of the GEO
importancy. Um, there's a few pillars um
that will be present. Um, we'll have to
quickly um close it, but if you have
more questions, of course, you can
contact us directly on LinkedIn or
through the QR code. Um, but basically
there are those five different pillars
that you need to to develop as well. um
that we can go a bit more into detail in
the FAQ for the next five minutes. Um
for those who can stay a bit over um but
if you have more questions for us, we're
present at Vivitech. Um our managing
director will be speaking there as well.
Um so you can book a meeting at our
stand for that. Um and uh if you need
any support from us um we're here we're
AI first company and we think AI is the
future. Um so if you want to boost your
visibility on AI go or SEO we we can
help as well. Um and now for those who
have five minutes, we'll try to answer a
bit more questions. Um the recording and
the presentation will be sent. So don't
worry if you need to leave. Um you'll be
able to to see our response to any
questions. Um I don't know, Flora, if
you have any already anything you want
to add that we perhaps went a bit over
quickly.
>> Uh no, I saw maybe some questions
regarding the tool. I think it can be
interesting to uh answer that. Um I have
Remy asking um about the the tool that
we have and how do we verify if our
client is using best practices on
Reddit. So basically uh with our client
we have um uh consulting um cosmetic
phase when we help him to better
understand the platform, how to use it,
how to answer and we are uh helping them
uh in order to have the best uh answer.
So we can like uh create with them hand
in hand the answer that they want to
push. Uh so this is how we are uh
working with them. I don't know if you
have
>> no
>> no it's I think it's pretty pretty it.
>> Yeah. Um I saw a question about uh in
France it's been quite upvoted. Um if
you have questions put them in the
question section or you can upvote
questions that you find are interesting.
We'll try to go through the most upvoted
one. Um I see a question about is Reddit
used as much as a source in in France in
LLM answers. Um and so for now we we do
see that quite a bit. Um we I don't have
the exact figures here but we can try to
send that to you. Um we're always doing
um research with Eskimos with barometers
and and uh other type of research. Um
and so we have white papers usually
coming out. Um and I think we should
have that quite quickly as well on on
topic. Also, I saw something about um
translation on Reddit. I don't know if
we mentioned that, but we have uh on
Reddit, you have like automatic
translation. So, if you are you speak in
French, you can reach uh maybe uh
English speaker. Uh so, it will depend
on the of the audience that you have.
they already speak in English. It's
better to write in English and espec es
especially uh that the data in Reddit is
really important in the US and on like
English speaking countries. So that's
it. Yeah,
>> I see. Um at the bottom left you
currently have one of our research that
we've done with Ipsos um to see how the
search habits are evolving in France. So
if you want to download that you you
have that as well. Um
any other question that we haven't
answered for our presentation?
Um how do you leverage Reddit for a
direct bottom of funnel lead generation?
I think that's what we've tried to say a
bit earlier is that it's not going to
directly convert. Um it's more of
building that foundation on LLM's um
that will convert on the on the medium
to short to long term. Um so it's
important to build that kind of capital
um for the future.
I see a point about sharing an same
account with other people of the team.
Uh so as I said um like Reddit uh have
like can flag like same IP
fingerprinting. So it will be more
interesting to have different uh
accounts if you can uh so maybe you and
some other person on your team uh that
can be really interesting. Um and it
will maybe help to increase the
activity. Uh if you want for example
answer um questions in other subreddits
if you have consultants or employee that
can do that to help you and to push your
brand it will be really interesting.
Yeah.
>> Um there's a person that's asking if
they should create a subreddit. I think
that's actually a great question for
your brand. Um so I think it really
depends. Um, if you're a very small
brand or startup, I wouldn't recommend
directly creating your own subreddits.
Um, however, as you're growing, um, you
should try to aim for it. Um, but it
really depends, I think, on your size
and kind of in the niche you're in and
how much people are searching for it.
Um, so if if you want to build, I think
if you're for example, um, in Eskimos,
we build our own subreddits as there's a
lot of research around go and and we
hope to stay above the curve. Um, but
for example, I think if if you're in new
cars or that type of thing, perhaps it's
too soon um, you know, compared to
Nissan or that type of big subreddits
that you might have. Um, but you can
definitely participate and we strongly
encourage you as a brand to participate
on those subreddits to post to comment
and to kind of develop your authority
there already. And then once people get
to know a bit more your brand um, you
can definitely try to develop there as
well. And there is another point uh
question if you if I already have a
community and I want to create a
subreddit can I do it directly or do I
have to get a karma before? No, you can
do it directly because your celebrity or
community will be your own rule. Uh so
you will be the one that will animate
the community and other also can publish
respecting the rules that you put in
place but you can yeah directly do it.
Yeah, I think I see a question as well
from Thomas asking if is Kora similar to
Reddit. Um, it's quite similar. Um,
we're seeing it being cited a bit as
well. Um, so perhaps you could try to,
you know, perhaps not duplicate directly
your answers your post, but try to make
it slightly different with the same
topics um um for that. Um, but it is
getting important to be present on Kora.
Of course, everyone has limited
resources. is I think it goes hand
inhand with what I was trying to present
a bit earlier with every every pillar
you can't be on all pillar and be you
know have that much resource so you need
to focus um so it's really important to
understand that depending on your niche
you should try to focus um on on on a
specific pillar um which we can help on
if you need any help um but of course uh
it's it's about choosing your battles
right and so if it's Reddit or Kora and
you have limited resources I would 100%
recommend focusing a bit more on Reddit
For now, as we've seen, it's the
training data um mainly used by by Lens.
>> I'm sure
>> we'll try to answer perhaps a few more
questions as we're a bit over. Um I
don't know if there's any recent ones
that have come up.
>> Maybe this one. I don't know if we
already answer it, but um
uh do you uh need um do you need to
encourage your customer to post on
Reddit? uh it is not like the trust
pilot um kind of platform. So you can
just say to the customer to push uh your
brand like that because the comments for
example of your customer need to answer
a post questions of someone that is uh
searching for an answer. So it is not on
this uh this way that I will uh do my uh
strategy. I will uh probably or like
create a brand account or create a
professional like expert account uh
better than pushing my customers to
plus.
>> Yeah, I think um you can ask your
customers what you can do actually is
when there's comparisons. So for
example, HubSpot versus Salesforce, you
can directly tell them to you know post
on that current post. So comment saying
which one they prefer. Um so indeed your
brand um that could be super helpful.
comparisons are are a great way to to
push um your brand as people type that a
lot in NLMs. Um do we have a trial
version? Um you can ask with our sales
team. Um you can have a fiveminute call
with them. They can also answer any of
your questions that you have here that
we haven't responded. I think um we
respond to most of them. Um please feel
free to to send us a a message um on our
email address uh at contactes eskimos.co
co. UK or you can directly um book a
quick call with the sales team. Um if
there's any other webinars that you're
interested in or if you want a part two
of Reddit to for us to go a bit more
into detail um we can do that as well.
Um thank you very much everyone. I think
it was had a great time.
>> Yeah.
>> And uh and we'll talk later.
>> Thank you. Cheers everyone.
>> Bye.